Previously, when we created a variable that held an immutable object,
前面 当我们创建一个包含不可变的对象时
the value of that immutable object was saved in memory.
不可变的对象中的值将会存储到内存中
Here, we create a name with value Jim,
在这里 我们来创建一个值为 Jim 的变量 name
and assign it to another variable called student.
然后把 name 赋值给另一个称为 student 的变量
It is the value Jim that is assigned to student.
于是有 值 Jim 被赋值给变量 student
So when we reassign name to update it to Tim,
因此 当我们将变量 name 的值更新为 Tim时
this change is not reflected in the value of student.
这个值的更改不会影响到变量 student 中的值
Lists are different from strings as they are mutable.
列表（List）不同于字符串（string） 因为它是值可更改的
Here, we create a list of scores and assign the same list to the variable grades: B,
在这里 我们创建一个列表 scores 并将此列表分配给变量 grades
C, A, D, B,
B C A D B A
A, six of them,
此列表拥有这6个元素
and when we change or mutate the scores list making the fourth grade B instead of D,
当我们更改或改变列表 scores 使得第四个等级值 B 更改成 D
this affects both scores and grades.
这将同时影响 scores 和 grades 这两个变量
Both scores and grades are variable names for the same underlying list,
其中 scores 和 grades 两个变量同时指向同一个列表
and either name can be used to access and change that list.
而且这两个变量都能获得并更改这个列表的值
The behavior of variables containing mutable and immutable objects are very different,
由此可见 变量包含可变对象和包含不可变对象 对于这两种变量的行为是非常不同的
and might even seem surprising at times.
而且 有时甚至可能会令人惊讶
Experiment, use the print functions and double check your work where you
于是 在实验中 你最好使用打印功能并仔细检查你的工作和代码
can to make sure that your programs correctly keep track of their data.
这样才可以确保你的程序正确地跟踪他们的数据
While you experiment with lists,
当你在使用列表（list）这个数据结构的时候
there are some useful functions you should get familiar with.
有一些你应该熟悉的非常有用的函数
Len returns how many elements are in a list,
函数 len 返回列表（list）中的元素个数
max returns the greatest element of a list.
函数 max 返回列表（list）中值最大的元素
How the greatest element is determined depends on what type of objects are in your list.
如何确定最大元素这取决于列表中的对象类型
The maximum element in a list of numbers is the largest number.
数字列表中的最大元素是最大数字
The maximum element in a list of strings is
字符串列表中最大元素是
the element that would occur last if the list was sorted alphabetically.
按字母表顺序的最后一个字母
That's reticulated python for this list.
这是 python 语言对关于列表 list 的一个特点
R is the largest letter alphabetically.
而对于 R 语言 则是在字母表中的最大的字母
In other words, greater than B,
换句话说 大于 B
A, B, and A.
A B 和 A
This works because the max function is
得到这样的结果是因为函数 max
defined in terms of the greater than comparison operator.
取决于内部的“大于”比较器
The greater than comparison operator is defined for many non-numeric types.
“大于”比较器可能会用于定义很多非数字的类型
If you're working with objects that can be compared with this,
如果你在处理一些可以用于互相比较的对象时
then you can use max on a list of the objects.
那么 对于该对象的列表 你就可以使用函数 max
For strings, the standard comparison is alphabetical.
关于字符串 标准的比较时按字母表进行的
So the maximum of this list is the element that appears last alphabetically.
因此 字符串列表的最大值是出现在字母表上的最后元素
Although you can create lists that hold a mix of elements of many types as you see here,
尽管你能够创建包含不同类型的元素的列表 比如 00:02:35,455 --&gt; 00:02:39,050 数字和文本 但是函数 max 是不支持
lists that contain elements from different incomparable types.
那些包含不可比较的不同类型的列表的
Here, you can see it breaks with this mix of datatypes.
否则 你将会看到程序会因混淆数据类型而断开
Min is the opposite of max and returns the smallest element in a list.
函数 min 是函数 max 的相反操作 然后返回列表中的最小元素
Sorted returns a copy of a list in order from
函数 sorted 返回一个对该列表排完序的列表的复制列表
smallest to largest leaving the original list unchanged.
返回的列表从小到大排好序 并且不会影响原先的列表
Here, for a list called sizes,
这里举个例子 对于名为 sizes 的列表
the order is ascending.
它的顺序是升序
You can sort from largest to smallest by
你可以通过添加可选的参数 "reverse=True"
adding the optional argument reverse equals true.
让它变成从大到小排序
Now, the order is descending.
于是 现在这个列表的顺序便是降序了